<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lambda on Git Push and Run</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/tags/lambda/</link><description>Recent content in Lambda on Git Push and Run</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>it</language><copyright>© 2026 Manuel Fedele</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 16:45:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/tags/lambda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building an AI-Powered Document Processing Pipeline on AWS</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/building-ai-document-processing-pipeline-aws/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 16:45:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/building-ai-document-processing-pipeline-aws/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 A serverless document processing pipeline on AWS that uses LLMs to extract structured data from unstructured documents — invoices, contracts, reports — at scale. No GPU clusters required.
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>Insurance companies process millions of documents every year: police reports, medical records, invoices, repair estimates. Traditionally, human operators read each document, classify it, extract the relevant fields, and enter the data into the claims system. This is slow, expensive, and error-prone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Aws Opensearch as Monitoring Tool</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/aws-opensearch-as-monitoring-tool/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 08:42:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/aws-opensearch-as-monitoring-tool/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 In today&amp;rsquo;s distributed systems, logging and monitoring play a crucial role in detecting anomalies and ensuring system health. AWS Lambda and OpenSearch are often paired to deliver efficient, scalable logging solutions. However, complexities can arise when these resources live in&amp;hellip;
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>In today&amp;rsquo;s distributed systems, logging and monitoring play a crucial role in detecting anomalies and ensuring system health. AWS Lambda and OpenSearch are often paired to deliver efficient, scalable logging solutions. However, complexities can arise when these resources live in separate AWS accounts. This blog post will guide you through the process of sending AWS Lambda logs from Account A to an OpenSearch cluster in Account B using Terraform as the Infrastructure as Code (IAC) tool and GitLab for CI/CD pipelines.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>