<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security on Git Push and Run</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/tags/security/</link><description>Recent content in Security on Git Push and Run</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2026 Manuel Fedele</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 10:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://manuelfedele.github.io/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Shipping a DORA Compliance Tool from Zero to Production in One Day</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/posts/shipping-a-dora-compliance-tool-from-zero-to-prod/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/posts/shipping-a-dora-compliance-tool-from-zero-to-prod/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 I spent a single session building a DORA-compliant Third Party Management tool from scratch, adding Microsoft Entra ID SSO, migrating the entire infrastructure from CloudFormation to Terraform, deploying to both qual and prod on ECS Fargate, and fixing a cascade of real-world deployment problems along the way. Here is an honest account of what broke and how I fixed it.
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>I built a DORA-compliant Third Party Management (TPM) tool: a Django + React application for managing ICT provider lifecycles, risk assessments, and regulatory registers. Then I wired up Microsoft Entra ID SSO, containerized it, and deployed it to AWS ECS Fargate using a Terraform pipeline, in a corporate environment full of proxies, permission boundaries, and shared infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Implementing a JWT Issuer in Go</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/posts/jwt-issuer-in-go/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 17:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/posts/jwt-issuer-in-go/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 JSON Web Tokens (JWT) have become the de facto standard for implementing stateless authentication in modern web applications. In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll implement a secure JWT issuer in Go, covering both basic implementation and advanced security considerations.
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>JSON Web Tokens (JWT) have become the de facto standard for implementing stateless authentication in modern web applications. In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll implement a secure JWT issuer in Go, covering both basic implementation and advanced security considerations.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>