<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Terraform on Git Push and Run</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/tags/terraform/</link><description>Recent content in Terraform on Git Push and Run</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2026 Manuel Fedele</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 10:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://manuelfedele.github.io/tags/terraform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Shipping a DORA Compliance Tool from Zero to Production in One Day</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/posts/shipping-a-dora-compliance-tool-from-zero-to-prod/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/posts/shipping-a-dora-compliance-tool-from-zero-to-prod/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 I spent a single session building a DORA-compliant Third Party Management tool from scratch, adding Microsoft Entra ID SSO, migrating the entire infrastructure from CloudFormation to Terraform, deploying to both qual and prod on ECS Fargate, and fixing a cascade of real-world deployment problems along the way. Here is an honest account of what broke and how I fixed it.
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>I built a DORA-compliant Third Party Management (TPM) tool: a Django + React application for managing ICT provider lifecycles, risk assessments, and regulatory registers. Then I wired up Microsoft Entra ID SSO, containerized it, and deployed it to AWS ECS Fargate using a Terraform pipeline, in a corporate environment full of proxies, permission boundaries, and shared infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ECS Fargate Production Patterns That Actually Work</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/posts/ecs-fargate-production-patterns/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:20:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/posts/ecs-fargate-production-patterns/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 A set of battle-tested ECS Fargate patterns I apply to every production service — covering Spot strategies, deployment circuit breakers, ARM64 migration, health checks, and Aurora Serverless v2 cost optimization.
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve deployed and managed many containerized services on ECS Fargate. Over time, a set of patterns has emerged that I apply consistently to every new service. This post documents those patterns with Terraform examples, covering everything from Fargate Spot strategies to deployment circuit breakers and ARM64 migration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Managing Multi-Account AWS Infrastructure with Terraform Workspaces</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/posts/multi-account-aws-terraform-workspaces/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 09:15:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/posts/multi-account-aws-terraform-workspaces/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 Managing Terraform across multiple AWS accounts and environments without duplicating code. This post covers the workspace pattern, remote state, cross-account role assumptions, and the module structure that scales from 3 accounts to 30.
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>When you&amp;rsquo;re managing infrastructure across dozens of AWS accounts, you need patterns that scale. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll share the approach I use to manage multi-account, multi-environment AWS infrastructure using Terraform workspaces, modular code, and a consistent tagging strategy.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>