<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Git Push and Run</title>
    
    
    
    <link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Git Push and Run</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 14:57:41 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://manuelfedele.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a template for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/posts/create-template-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 14:57:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/posts/create-template-hugo/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Introduction # This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Deploy Machine Learning Model With Python</title>
      <link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/posts/how-to-deploy-machine-learning-model-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 16:30:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/posts/how-to-deploy-machine-learning-model-with-python/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Today we&amp;rsquo;ll se how to deploy a machine learning model with fastapi. We&amp;rsquo;ll start with a simple example of a fastapi server that can classify the content of an image.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with our project structure
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ src/ __init__.py prediction_model.py settings.py ▾ models/ mobilenet_v2.h5 main.py I like to have a settings.py file to store project base settings, as Django does.
We will start by populating the settings.py file with useful values, as the base directory, the model directory etc, this will come in handy later.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poetry No Module Seed via App Data</title>
      <link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/posts/poetry-no-module-seed-via-app-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 15:15:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/posts/poetry-no-module-seed-via-app-data/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          For my last project, I used poetry to manage dependencies and package my code. Poetry comes with all the tools you might need to manage your projects in a deterministic way.
Anyway, after running poetry init in an existing project, I tried to let poetry create a virtuale environment, by adding the first dependecy, but when I did poetry add twisted it suddenly hang out, printing:
No module named &amp;#39;virtualenv.seed.via_app_data&amp;#39; Why is that?
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 14:56:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          I am an experienced Software Engineer adept in bringing forth expertise in design, installation, testing and maintenance of web stacks. Proficient in various platforms, languages, and embedded systems. Experienced with the latest cutting edge development tools and procedures. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of a productive team.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>