<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Design Patterns on Git Push and Run</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/tags/design-patterns/</link><description>Recent content in Design Patterns on Git Push and Run</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>it</language><copyright>© 2026 Manuel Fedele</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 15:10:03 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/tags/design-patterns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Single Responsibility Principle</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/the-single-responsibility-principle/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 15:10:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/the-single-responsibility-principle/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 The Single Responsibility Principle (SRP) is a software design principle that states that a software module or component should have only one reason to change. This means that a module or component should have a single, narrowly defined responsibility and all of its features&amp;hellip;
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>The Single Responsibility Principle (SRP) is a software design principle that states that a software module or component should have only one reason to change. This means that a module or component should have a single, narrowly defined responsibility and all of its features should be related to that responsibility.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Implement Design Patterns With Golang</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/implement-desing-patterns-with-golang/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 13:16:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/implement-desing-patterns-with-golang/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 Design patterns are reusable solutions to common software design problems. They are a way to structure and organize code in a way that makes it easier to understand, maintain, and extend. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how to implement some popular design patterns in Go.
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>Design patterns are reusable solutions to common software design problems. They are a way to structure and organize code in a way that makes it easier to understand, maintain, and extend. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how to implement some popular design patterns in Go.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Use Interfaces in Golang</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/how-to-use-interfaces-in-golang/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 19:04:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/how-to-use-interfaces-in-golang/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 In Go, an interface is a type that defines a set of methods that a struct must implement in order to implement the interface. An interface defines the behavior or capabilities of a struct without specifying the implementation details. This allows different structs to implement&amp;hellip;
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>In Go, an interface is a type that defines a set of methods that a struct must implement in order to implement the interface. An interface defines the behavior or capabilities of a struct without specifying the implementation details. This allows different structs to implement the same interface in different ways, promoting loose coupling and flexibility in your code.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Implement Factory Design Pattern in Golang</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/implement-factory-design-pattern-golang/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 18:57:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/implement-factory-design-pattern-golang/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 To implement the factory design pattern in Go, you can create a factory function that returns an object that implements a common interface. This function can take parameters to specify the type of object to be created. Here is an example of how you might implement the factory&amp;hellip;
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>To implement the factory design pattern in Go, you can create a factory function that returns an object that implements a common interface. This function can take parameters to specify the type of object to be created. Here is an example of how you might implement the factory design pattern in Go:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>