<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Git on Git Push and Run</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/tags/git/</link><description>Recent content in Git on Git Push and Run</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>it</language><copyright>© 2026 Manuel Fedele</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 17:14:30 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Delete Git Branch Locally</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/how-to-delete-git-branch-locally/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 17:14:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/how-to-delete-git-branch-locally/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 To delete a Git branch locally, you can use the &lt;code>git branch&lt;/code> command with the &lt;code>-d&lt;/code> flag, followed by the name of the branch you want to delete. For example:
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>To delete a Git branch locally, you can use the &lt;code>git branch&lt;/code> command with the &lt;code>-d&lt;/code> flag, followed by the name of the branch you want to delete. For example:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight-wrapper">&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>git branch -d branch_name&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>This will delete the specified branch if it has already been fully merged into the current branch. If the branch has not been fully merged, you can use the -D flag instead, which will force the deletion of the branch.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Undo Most Recent Local Git Commit</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/how-to-undo-most-recent-local-git-commit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 17:09:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/how-to-undo-most-recent-local-git-commit/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 Git is a version control system that allows developers to track changes to their codebase and collaborate with others. One of the useful features of Git is the ability to revert changes that have been made to the codebase. In this article, we will look at how to undo the most&amp;hellip;
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>Git is a version control system that allows developers to track changes to their codebase and collaborate with others. One of the useful features of Git is the ability to revert changes that have been made to the codebase. In this article, we will look at how to undo the most recent local commits in Git.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Is the Difference Between Git Pull and Git Fetch</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/what-is-the-difference-between-git-pull-and-git-fetch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 17:16:40 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/what-is-the-difference-between-git-pull-and-git-fetch/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 Git is a version control system that is widely used in software development to track and manage changes to source code. Two of the most common Git commands that developers use to retrieve updates from a remote repository are &lt;code>git pull&lt;/code> and &lt;code>git fetch&lt;/code>. While these two commands&amp;hellip;
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>Git is a version control system that is widely used in software development to track and manage changes to source code. Two of the most common Git commands that developers use to retrieve updates from a remote repository are &lt;code>git pull&lt;/code> and &lt;code>git fetch&lt;/code>. While these two commands may seem similar at first glance, they have some important differences that are worth understanding.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>