<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python on Git Push and Run</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on Git Push and Run</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>it</language><copyright>© 2026 Manuel Fedele</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 09:30:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Costruire un Assistente SRE AI da Zero: Architettura di un Investigatore Infrastrutturale Autonomo</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/building-ai-sre-assistant-from-scratch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 09:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/building-ai-sre-assistant-from-scratch/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 Cosa succederebbe se il tuo ingegnere di on-call non dormisse mai, avesse accesso istantaneo a ogni repository e ogni account AWS, e potesse tracciare un problema di produzione dal DNS al database in meno di un minuto? Questo articolo descrive ogni layer dell&amp;rsquo;architettura — dal sistema di autenticazione al framework agente, al registry dei tool, all&amp;rsquo;infrastruttura di streaming e al deployment.
&lt;/div>

&lt;div class="admonition relative overflow-hidden rounded-lg border-l-4 my-3 px-4 py-3 shadow-sm" data-type="note">
 &lt;div class="flex items-center gap-2 font-semibold text-inherit">
 &lt;div class="flex shrink-0 h-5 w-5 items-center justify-center text-lg">&lt;span class="relative block icon">&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path fill="currentColor" d="M256 0C114.6 0 0 114.6 0 256s114.6 256 256 256s256-114.6 256-256S397.4 0 256 0zM256 128c17.67 0 32 14.33 32 32c0 17.67-14.33 32-32 32S224 177.7 224 160C224 142.3 238.3 128 256 128zM296 384h-80C202.8 384 192 373.3 192 360s10.75-24 24-24h16v-64H224c-13.25 0-24-10.75-24-24S210.8 224 224 224h32c13.25 0 24 10.75 24 24v88h16c13.25 0 24 10.75 24 24S309.3 384 296 384z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/span>&lt;/div>
 &lt;div class="grow">
 Nota
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>&lt;div class="admonition-content mt-3 text-base leading-relaxed text-inherit">&lt;p>Questo articolo descrive un assistente SRE AI costruito con l&amp;rsquo;SDK Strands Agents, Django, React e AWS. L&amp;rsquo;agente indaga autonomamente i problemi infrastrutturali combinando ragionamento LLM con integrazioni profonde in GitLab e AWS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Costruire un Agente AI per le Operazioni di Piattaforma</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/building-ai-powered-platform-operations-agent/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/building-ai-powered-platform-operations-agent/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 I team di platform engineering gestiscono un flusso costante di richieste ripetitive. Questo articolo mostra come costruire un agente AI che automatizza le attività comuni di piattaforma — provisioning utenti, rotazione chiavi, controlli di salute dei servizi — dando a un LLM accesso agli strumenti interni attraverso un&amp;rsquo;interfaccia di tool-calling strutturata.
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>I team di platform engineering gestiscono un flusso costante di richieste ripetitive: onboarding utenti, gestione API key, verifica dello stato dei servizi, rotazione credenziali. La maggior parte di questi compiti segue procedure ben definite che un umano esegue passo per passo. E se un agente AI potesse gestirle al suo posto?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Costruire una Pipeline di Elaborazione Documenti AI su AWS</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/building-ai-document-processing-pipeline-aws/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 16:45:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/building-ai-document-processing-pipeline-aws/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 Una pipeline serverless di elaborazione documenti su AWS che usa LLM per estrarre dati strutturati da documenti non strutturati — fatture, contratti, report — su larga scala. Nessun cluster GPU richiesto.
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>Le compagnie assicurative elaborano milioni di documenti ogni anno: verbali di polizia, cartelle cliniche, fatture, preventivi di riparazione. Tradizionalmente, operatori umani leggono ogni documento, lo classificano, ne estraggono i campi rilevanti e inseriscono i dati nel sistema dei sinistri. Questo è lento, costoso e soggetto a errori.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Use Protobuf With Fastapi</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/use-protobuf-with-fastapi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 16:00:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/use-protobuf-with-fastapi/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 Protocol buffers, also known as Protobuf, are a popular data serialization format used for communication between services. They are efficient, easy to use, and language-agnostic. In this article, we will look at how to use Protobuf with FastAPI, a modern, high-performance web&amp;hellip;
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>Protocol buffers, also known as Protobuf, are a popular data serialization format used for communication between services. They are efficient, easy to use, and language-agnostic. In this article, we will look at how to use Protobuf with FastAPI, a modern, high-performance web framework for building APIs with Python.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Understand Async Await in Python</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/understand-async-await-in-python/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 14:50:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/understand-async-await-in-python/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 Async/await is a powerful programming construct that allows you to write asynchronous code in a synchronous-like style. It was introduced in Python 3.5 as part of the asyncio module and has become a popular choice for writing concurrent and parallel code in Python.
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>Async/await is a powerful programming construct that allows you to write asynchronous code in a synchronous-like style. It was introduced in Python 3.5 as part of the asyncio module and has become a popular choice for writing concurrent and parallel code in Python.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Create a Webserver With Fastapi and Uvicorn</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/create-webserver-with-fastapi-and-uvicorn/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 14:08:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/create-webserver-with-fastapi-and-uvicorn/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 FastAPI is a modern, fast, web framework for building APIs with Python 3.7 and above. It is built on top of Starlette, a lightweight ASGI framework, and uses the uvicorn ASGI server.
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>FastAPI is a modern, fast, web framework for building APIs with Python 3.7 and above. It is built on top of Starlette, a lightweight ASGI framework, and uses the uvicorn ASGI server.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is an example of how to create a web server with FastAPI and uvicorn:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Does Yield Keyword Do in Python</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/what-does-yield-keyword-do-in-python/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 10:19:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/what-does-yield-keyword-do-in-python/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 The keyword &amp;ldquo;yield&amp;rdquo; is a important part of the Python programming language, and it can be used in a number of different ways. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a closer look at what the yield keyword does in Python, and how it can be used to create more efficient and powerful programs.
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>The keyword &amp;ldquo;yield&amp;rdquo; is a important part of the Python programming language, and it can be used in a number of different ways. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a closer look at what the yield keyword does in Python, and how it can be used to create more efficient and powerful programs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Poetry No Module Seed via App Data</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/poetry-no-module-seed-via-app-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 15:15:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/poetry-no-module-seed-via-app-data/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 For my last project, I used &lt;strong>poetry&lt;/strong> to manage dependencies and package my code. Poetry comes with all the tools you might need to manage your projects in a deterministic way.
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>For my last project, I used &lt;strong>poetry&lt;/strong> to manage dependencies and package my code.
Poetry comes with all the tools you might need to manage your projects in a deterministic way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, after running poetry init in an existing project, I tried to let poetry create a virtuale environment, by adding the first dependecy, but when I did poetry add twisted it suddenly hang out, printing:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>