<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud on Git Push and Run</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/tags/cloud/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud on Git Push and Run</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>it</language><copyright>© 2026 Manuel Fedele</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:20:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ECS Fargate Production Patterns That Actually Work</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/ecs-fargate-production-patterns/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:20:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/ecs-fargate-production-patterns/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 A set of battle-tested ECS Fargate patterns I apply to every production service — covering Spot strategies, deployment circuit breakers, ARM64 migration, health checks, and Aurora Serverless v2 cost optimization.
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve deployed and managed many containerized services on ECS Fargate. Over time, a set of patterns has emerged that I apply consistently to every new service. This post documents those patterns with Terraform examples, covering everything from Fargate Spot strategies to deployment circuit breakers and ARM64 migration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Managing Multi-Account AWS Infrastructure with Terraform Workspaces</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/multi-account-aws-terraform-workspaces/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 09:15:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/it/posts/multi-account-aws-terraform-workspaces/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 Managing Terraform across multiple AWS accounts and environments without duplicating code. This post covers the workspace pattern, remote state, cross-account role assumptions, and the module structure that scales from 3 accounts to 30.
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>When you&amp;rsquo;re managing infrastructure across dozens of AWS accounts, you need patterns that scale. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll share the approach I use to manage multi-account, multi-environment AWS infrastructure using Terraform workspaces, modular code, and a consistent tagging strategy.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>