<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Webserver on Git Push and Run</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/tags/webserver/</link><description>Recent content in Webserver on Git Push and Run</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2026 Manuel Fedele</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 14:08:35 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://manuelfedele.github.io/tags/webserver/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building Production APIs with FastAPI: Pydantic, Dependency Injection, and Deployment</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/posts/create-webserver-with-fastapi-and-uvicorn/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 14:08:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/posts/create-webserver-with-fastapi-and-uvicorn/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 FastAPI combines Python type hints with automatic OpenAPI documentation and near-Go performance. It has become the default choice for Python APIs. This post covers the patterns that matter in production: Pydantic models, dependency injection, background tasks, and multi-worker deployment.
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>FastAPI is not a thin wrapper around Starlette. The combination of Pydantic v2 for validation, &lt;code>Depends()&lt;/code> for dependency injection, and async-native request handling makes it the closest Python equivalent to a typed HTTP framework. The original version of this post had a broken handler signature and no production content. This is the rebuild.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building Production HTTP Services in Go</title><link>https://manuelfedele.github.io/posts/how-to-create-a-webserver-in-golang/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 19:14:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://manuelfedele.github.io/posts/how-to-create-a-webserver-in-golang/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400 !mb-9 text-xl">
 Go&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code>net/http&lt;/code> standard library is production-ready. With Go 1.22+ enhanced routing, method and path pattern matching are built in. You do not need a framework for most services &amp;ndash; but you do need to configure timeouts, graceful shutdown, and middleware correctly from the start.
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>Most Go HTTP tutorials show &lt;code>http.ListenAndServe(&amp;quot;:8080&amp;quot;, nil)&lt;/code> and call it a day. That code will run, but it will leak goroutines under load, hang forever on slow clients, and crash non-gracefully when you deploy a new version. This post covers what a production-ready Go HTTP service actually looks like, using only the standard library for the core, with a note on when a router library pays off.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>